PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM
J	Kim, HS; Jeong, SY; Lee, JH; Kim, BE; Kim, JW; Jeong, SW; Kim, IK				Kim, HS; Jeong, SY; Lee, JH; Kim, BE; Kim, JW; Jeong, SW; Kim, IK			Induction of apoptosis in human leukemia cells by 3-deazaadenosine is mediated by caspase-3-like activity	EXPERIMENTAL AND MOLECULAR MEDICINE												9-Deazaadenosine (DZA), one of the potent inhibitors of S-adenosylhomocysteine hydrolase, is known to possess several biological properties including an induction of apoptosis. To evaluate a possibility that DZA may be utilized for the treatment of human leukemia, we studied molecular events of cell death induced by DZA in human leukemia HL-60 and U-937 cells. DZA induced a specific cleavage of poly ADP-ribose polymerase (PARP) and an activation of the cysteine protease caspase-3/CPP32 which is known to cleave PARP. DZA-mediated nuclear DNA-fragmentation was completely blocked in the presence of a universal inhibitor of caspases (z-VAD-fmk) or the specific inhibitor of caspase-3 (z-DEVD-fmk) unlike of cycloheximide (CHX). DNA fragmentation was preceded by the lowering of c-myc mRNA in the DZA treated cells. In addition, DZA-induced apoptosis was blocked by pretreatment with adenosine transporter inhibitors such as nitrobenzylthioinosine (NBTI) and dipyridamole (DPD). Taken together, these results demonstrate that DZA-Induced apoptosis initiated through an active transport of DZA into human leukemia cells, is dependent on the caspase-3-like activity without de nova synthesis of proteins and possibly involves c-myc down-regulation.																	1226-3613					DEC 31	2000	32	4					197	203								WOS:000166183400004	11190270				
J	Chinenov, Y; Coombs, C; Martin, ME				Chinenov, Y; Coombs, C; Martin, ME			Isolation of a bi-directional promoter directing expression of the mouse GABP alpha and ATP synthase coupling factor 6 genes	GENE												The GA-binding protein (GABP) is a ubiquitous heteromeric transcription factor implicated in the regulation of several genes involved in mitochondrial energy metabolism including subunits of cytochrome c oxidase, ATP synthase, and mitochondrial transcription factor 1 (mtTF1). GABP alpha subunit binds the PEA3/Ets binding sites (EBS), while GABP beta contains a transcription activation domain and mediates alpha beta dimer and alpha (2)beta (2) tetramer formation essential for activation of transcription. Here we report the cloning of 2449 bp of the mouse (m) GABP alpha promoter region including 201 bp of the 5' end of the published mGABP alpha cDNA sequence. Surprisingly, sequences homologous to the 5'UTR of mouse, rat and human mitochondrial ATP synthase coupling factor 6 (ATPsynCF6) cDNAs were found165-240 bp upstream of the mGABP alpha cDNA. A search of the non-redundant nucleotide database revealed a human genomic sequence derived from chromosome 21 (21q22) bearing significant homology to the mGABP alpha /ATPsynCF6 promoter region and encompassed the entire hGABP alpha and hATP-synCF6 genes. Primer extension analysis revealed multiple transcription start sites for both mGABP alpha and mATPsynCF6 mRNAs that mapped near the published cDNA 5' ends. Sequence analysis identified several binding sites upstream of the GABP alpha cDNA sequence including sites for GABP (-86, -104, -169, -257, and -994), YY1 (-57), Spl (-242 and -226), and NRF1 (-5). No 'TATA' motif was identified near either the GABPa or ATPsynCF6 transcription start sites. The human and mouse promoters retain significant sequence identity including binding sites for several tissue-specific transcription factors. Transient transfection assays using Luciferase reporter constructs containing the intergenic region and flanking sequences confirmed that this region of DNA promotes transcription in both directions. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0378-1119					DEC 31	2000	261	2					311	320		10.1016/S0378-1119(00)00500-X						WOS:000166956600015	11167019				
J	Lantinga-van Leeuwen, IS; van Garderen, E; Rutteman, GR; Mol, JA				Lantinga-van Leeuwen, IS; van Garderen, E; Rutteman, GR; Mol, JA			Cloning and cellular localization of the canine progesterone receptor: co-localization with growth hormone in the mammary gland	JOURNAL OF STEROID BIOCHEMISTRY AND MOLECULAR BIOLOGY												The mammary gland has been found to express the gene encoding growth hormone (GH) in several species. Within the mammary gland, it may act as an autocrine paracrine growth factor for cyclic epithelial changes. and may be a determinant in mammary carcinogenrsis. In the dog, progestins enhance mammary GH expression. To elucidate the mechanism of progestin-induced mammary GH expression. the canine progestorone receptor (PR) is characterized and the cellular localization of the PR in normal and tumorous mammary tissues is examined. Sequence analysis of the canine PR revealed two in-frame ATG codons, encoding a putative PR-B protein of 939 amino acids and a putative PR-A protein of 765 amino acids. Western blot analysis indicated that both isoforms occur in uterus and mammary plant issues. Immunohistochemical analysis of the PR revealed that the PR was differentially expressed in mammary tissue. with many PR-positive epithelial cells in the proliferation phase of the glandular tissue and a low number of PR-positive cells in differentiated mammary tissue. Stromal and myoepithelial cells had no specific PR staining. Mammary tumours had a variety of staining patterns, including no staining. normal nuclear staining, marked heterogeneous immunoreactivity and perinuclear staining of tumorous epithelial cells and cytoplasmic-staining of spindle cells. Double staining showed that all GH-producing cells were positive for PR, whereas not all PR containing cells stained for GH. It is concluded that the activated PR may transactivate GH expression in the mammary gland within the same cell and functions as a pre-requisite transcription factor. However. during malignant transformation this regulation may be lost. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.																	0960-0760					DEC 31	2000	75	4-5					219	228		10.1016/S0960-0760(00)00173-4						WOS:000167567400003	11282275				
J	Han, JA; Park, SC				Han, JA; Park, SC			Transglutaminase-dependent modulation of transcription factor Sp1 activity	MOLECULES AND CELLS												Modification of transcription factors would result in significant changes in the expression of related genes. Recently, the presence of transglutaminase (TGase) has been reported in nuclei, the biological significances of which have attracted a great concern. In this study, we tested the possibility that nuclear TGase would crosslink and regulate the activity of a glutamine-rich transcription factor Sp1. The addition of purified guinea pig liver TGase increased the binding activity of Sp1 to the target DNA sequence by gel electrophoretic mobility shift assay. The activity of the human p21(WAF1) promoter containing six Sp1 binding sites was increased by the cotransfection of the TGase 2 gene, and two Spl sites at -82 and -69, relative to the transcription start site, were essential for the increased activity in human renal embryonic 293T cells. The activity of a minimal promoter containing three consensus Sp1 binding sites was increased by co-transfection of human TGase 2 gene. The amount of Sp1 protein was increased dramatically in TGase 2-transfected 293T cells and the Sp1 protein itself from HeLa cell nuclear extracts was crosslinked readily by-purified TGase at 37 degreesC in the presence of Ca2+. These results suggest that the nuclear TGase might modulate the activity of the Spl transcription factor probably via the posttranslational or transcriptional modification of the factor by TGase.																	1016-8478					DEC 31	2000	10	6					612	618		10.1007/s100590000020						WOS:000170492100002	11211864				
J	Lee, JH; Sung, BW; Youn, HJ; Park, JH				Lee, JH; Sung, BW; Youn, HJ; Park, JH			Identification, expression, and nuclear location of murine Mage-b2 protein, a tumor-associated antigen	MOLECULES AND CELLS												MAGE-1, which was originally identified by reacting with cytolytic T lymphocytes derived from the blood of melanoma patients, is a member of a gene family consisting of 17 structurally related genes. The MAGE genes are expressed only in the testis among normal tissues and in a number of human tumors of various histological types. Murine MAGE (also called SMAGE or Mage) genes were found in a study aimed at detecting mouse genes homologous to human MAGE genes. However, the biological functions of MAGE and Mage are currently unknown. To understand the biological functions of Mage, in the present study a recombinant SMAGE2 (Mage-b2) protein of 43 kDa was produced and monoclonal antibodies reactive with Mage-b2 protein were generated. One monoclonal antibody, smpG4A, specifically recognized a 43 kDa protein in lysates of Mage-b2 mRNA-positive sarcoma cells and of the testis. Immunohistochemistry showed that Mage-b2 is located in the nucleus of Mage-b2 mRNA-positive sarcoma cells. These results should contribute to understanding the biological functions of Mage.																	1016-8478					DEC 31	2000	10	6					647	653		10.1007/s100590000025						WOS:000170492100007	11211869				
J	Somerfield, PJ; Supaporn, Y; Aryuthaka, C				Somerfield, PJ; Supaporn, Y; Aryuthaka, C			The effects of green mussel Perna viridis (L.) (Mollusca : Mytilidae) culture on nematode community structure in the Gulf of Thailand	RAFFLES BULLETIN OF ZOOLOGY												Culture of the green mussel Perna viridis (L.) in Thai coastal waters is almost exclusively based on extensive pole culture, where spat are allowed to settle naturally on densely planted poles in shallow waters close to the shore. Such culture is limited in terms of space, and the shallow inshore regions suitable for it are vulnerable to pollution. There is immense potential for the development of suspended culture in Thai waters. In addition to increasing the yield and quality of the product, suspended cultures offer additional benefits such as providing habitats for the development of juvenile fish, and providing refugia from overfishing in relatively open waters. This study examines one potential drawback of suspended mussel culture in shallow waters such as are found in large areas of the Gulf of Thailand, namely the impact of such culture on the benthic communities. Nematode genera have been shown to be sensitive to ongoing physical and biological disturbance. In this study univariate and nonparametric multivariate analyses of nematode abundances are used to measure the extent of benthic impact resulting from a mussel raft. Although large differences in community structure are found beneath the raft, the areal extent of these changes is limited. It is concluded that if problems related to water quality and infrastructure can be dealt with, the localised benthic impact of such culture methods for the green mussel should not prevent their development in Thai coastal waters.				Somerfield, Paul/J-9189-2014	Somerfield, Paul/0000-0002-7581-5621												0217-2445					DEC 31	2000	48	2					263	272								WOS:000166441500010					
J	Morozova, EA; Morozov, IB; Smithson, SB; Solodilov, L				Morozova, EA; Morozov, IB; Smithson, SB; Solodilov, L			Lithospheric boundaries and upper mantle heterogeneity beneath Russian Eurasia: evidence from the DSS profile QUARTZ	TECTONOPHYSICS					8th International Symposium on Deep Seismic Profiling of the Continents and their Margins	SEP 20-25, 1998	BARCELONA, SPAIN	Minist Educ & Cultura, Univ Barcelona, Int Lithosphere Programme, REFTEK, ENRESA				A combined interpretation of seismic data from the 3850-km-long Russian seismic profile QUARTZ using chemical and nuclear explosions reveals complex structure of the lithosphere related to the regional tectonics. Our analysis is focused on the structure of the uppermost mantle and based on 2D ray-tracing and inversion of the data from all 51 shots along the profile, on 2D attenuation measurements, and on the results of an analysis of the long-range P(n) phase. Three groups of reflectors within the lithosphere are associated with regional- to global boundaries previously recognized in stable continental environments. One almost continuous upper mantle boundary occurs at 65 to 80-km depth and another with an approximately 40-km-thick low-velocity zone (LVZ) occurs at 120-140 km depth. The shallow upper mantle blocks and the extensive interfaces indicate strong upper mantle heterogeneity imaged by this unique profile. The thickness of the lithosphere varies from 220 km under the Baltic Shield to about 120-130 km under the tectonically active Himalayan Altay-Sayan fold belt. Within the lower part of the lithosphere, a zone of lower velocity, increased attenuation, and varying thickness might be related to hydration and partial melting, Large structural differences related to tectonic ages and histories are characteristic for the entire lithosphere and extend 200-400 km into the asthenosphere. Analysis of QUARTZ data gives confident indication of seismic heterogeneity from crustal to regional mantle scales indicating strong involvement of the mantle in tectonic processes. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0040-1951					DEC 31	2000	329	1-4					333	344		10.1016/S0040-1951(00)00202-X						WOS:000166972400018					
J	Marchant, RE; Raghavachari, M				Marchant, RE; Raghavachari, M			Special issue: The atomic force microscope (AFM) - Preface	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES																													0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					299	299		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00196-X						WOS:000090030600001					
J	Jandt, KD; Finke, M; Cacciafesta, P				Jandt, KD; Finke, M; Cacciafesta, P			Aspects of the physical chemistry of polymers, biomaterials and mineralised tissues investigated with atomic force microscopy (AFM)	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Beyond being merely a tool for measuring surface topography, atomic force microscopy (AFM) has made significant contributions to various scientific areas dealing with physical chemistry processes. This paper presents aspects of the physical chemistry at surfaces and interfaces of polymers, biomaterials and tissues investigated with AFM. Selected examples presented include surface induced self-assembly of polymer blends, copolymer interfacial reinforcement of immiscible homopolymers, protein adsorption on biomaterials and erosion of mineralised human tissues. In these areas, AFM is a useful and versatile tool to study structural or dynamic sample properties including thermodynamically driven surface evolution of polymer surfaces, lateral surface composition of interfaces, adsorption processes, and the metrology of demineralisation phenomena. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					301	314		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00139-9						WOS:000090030600002					
J	Raghavachari, M; Tsai, HM; Kottke-Marchant, K; Marchant, RE				Raghavachari, M; Tsai, HM; Kottke-Marchant, K; Marchant, RE			Surface dependent structures of von Willebrand factor observed by AFM under aqueous conditions	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												von Willebrand factor (VWF) is a large multimeric plasma glycoprotein that adheres rapidly to biomaterial surfaces upon exposure to blood. The adsorbed structure influences subsequent functional interactions with other blood components that mediate surface induced thrombosis. To examine the surface-dependent properties of VWF, we compared the adsorbed structures of VWF molecules on two different surfaces: Mica, which is hydrophilic; and octadecyltrichlorosilane (OTS) modified glass, which is hydrophobic. Atomic force microscopy (AFM) was used to image adsorbed VWF under aqueous conditions at physiologic pH and ionic strength. Individual VWF molecules were clearly discernible on both surfaces. On the hydrophobic surface, VWF displayed compact tertiary structures with rare: examples of extended molecules. In addition, these data revealed intramolecular structural arrangements of the repeat units within VWF multimers. On the hydrophilic mica surface, VWF displayed extended structures in which intramolecular repeat units were exposed. The lateral dimensions of VWF on mica (640 +/- 161 x 303 +/- 113 nm were larger than on the hydrophobic OTS (256 +/- 74 x 152 +/- 62 nm, P < 0.005). Our results demonstrate how surface properties mediate the molecular level structure and probable function of VWF: and provide some essential groundwork to develop a mechanistic understandings of surface-induced thrombosis. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					315	324		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00140-5						WOS:000090030600003					
J	Persike, N; Pfeiffer, M; Guckenberger, R; Fritz, M				Persike, N; Pfeiffer, M; Guckenberger, R; Fritz, M			Changes in the surface structure of purple membrane upon illumination measured by atomic force microscopy	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Bacteriorhodopsin (BR patches with a diameter of 1 to 3 mum were investigated in their native state by atomic force microscopy (AFM in buffer solution. The patches were immobilized deposited and investigated on mica in 150 mM KCl and 10 mM Tris-buffer at pH 8. Under this buffer condition they adsorb preferred with their extracellular side to the solid support mica. The structure of the two-dimensional light adapted crystals was resolved with an imaging force of about 100 pN up to a resolution of 13 Angstrom. The topography of the surface gets smoother if an imaging force of 1000 pN was applied indicating that protruding structures are compressed. Upon illumination with white light, during imaging with a force of 200 pN, the surface structure of the BR lattice changed. The force- and light-induced structural changes were reversible. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					325	332		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00141-7						WOS:000090030600004					
J	Kuznetsov, YG; Malkin, AJ; Lucas, RW; McPherson, A				Kuznetsov, YG; Malkin, AJ; Lucas, RW; McPherson, A			Atomic force microscopy studies of icosahedral virus crystal growth	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Biological macromolecules and particularly viruses, provide excellent systems for the study of crystallization from solution because of their relatively large size. The kinetics of their crystallization is at least an order of magnitude less than for conventional systems, and their large size permits visualization, both of crystal lattices and individual particles, by techniques such as atomic force microscopy (AFM). This technique is especially powerful for biological macromolecules because it can be utilized in situ, in the crystallization mother liquor, over long periods of time without perturbing the growing crystals. We present here observations using AFM of the nucleation and growth of crystals of satellite tobacco mosaic virus, and some recordings as well of bromegrass mosaic virus. Correlations are made, where possible, with corresponding analyses using X-ray diffraction analysis. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					333	346		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00142-9						WOS:000090030600005					
J	Kim, H; Garavito, RM; Lal, R				Kim, H; Garavito, RM; Lal, R			Atomic force microscopy of the three-dimensional crystal of membrane protein, OmpC porin	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Three-dimensional microcrystals of OmpC osmoporin were air-dried slowly and imaged in air with an atomic force microscope (AFM). The overall structural features in AFM images are in good agreement with the X-ray diffraction data of these OmpC osmoporin crystals: monoclinic P2(1), with the unit cell constants a = 117.6 Angstrom, b = 110 Angstrom, c = 298.4 Angstrom, beta = 97 degrees. Such a good correspondence between X-ray diffraction and AFM data suggests that the slow and mild air-drying of these crystals did not induce any significant alterations in the crystal lattices as expected upon crystal dehydration. At the (100) crystal face, individual trimeric protein-detergent complexes were resolved. These results show the potential for studying the molecular structure of microcrystals of integral membrane proteins. This study also suggests that the crystal grew in a fashion of rapid two-dimensional expansion along the be plane followed by a slow deposition along the a axis, perhaps as a rate-limiting nucleation process. Thus, AFM imaging of air-dried crystals would also be of considerable use in the early stages of a project to grow large three-dimensional crystals of membrane proteins suitable for high-resolution X-ray diffraction studies. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					347	355		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00143-0						WOS:000090030600006					
J	Lee, I; Marchant, RE				Lee, I; Marchant, RE			Force measurements on platelet surfaces with high spatial resolution under physiological conditions	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Investigations on platelets are essential to understanding the regulation of hemostasis and thrombosis. Activated platelets undergo dramatic conformational and morphological changes mediated by numerous plasma proteins. AFM techniques can combine high spatial resolution with measurements of the mechanical properties of platelet surfaces. Here, we demonstrate two-dimensional force mapping over a human platelet adsorbed on glass under physiological buffer. The best resolution of platelet membrane elasticity we obtained was at 15.6 x 15.6 nm(2) pixel(-1). In addition, quantitative information on platelet surface charge density was extracted from individual force curves with the aid of DLVO theory. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Lee, Imshik/G-6129-2010	Lee, Imshik/0000-0002-0098-392X												0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					357	365		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00144-2						WOS:000090030600007					
J	Domke, J; Dannohl, S; Parak, WJ; Muller, O; Aicher, WK; Radmacher, M				Domke, J; Dannohl, S; Parak, WJ; Muller, O; Aicher, WK; Radmacher, M			Substrate dependent differences in morphology and elasticity of living osteoblasts investigated by atomic force microscopy	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												We have used the atomic force microscope (AFM) as a tool for testing the biocompatibility of implant materials by investigating the adhesion behavior of osteoblast cells in vitro. This technique allowed the investigation of cytomorphology and cytomechanical properties of livings cells on a submicrometer scale. Cell adhesion was investigated on Cobalt-Chromium (CoCr), Titanium (Ti) and Titanium-Vanadium (TiV) substrates, which are of great interest in the field of implant research. The elastic properties and the morphology of living osteoblasts on the metallic substrates were compared with those of osteoblasts cultured on glass and tissue culture polystyrene (PS). Furthermore, a characterization of the surface roughness of the substrates was performed and the surface coverage of proteins after incubation with cell culture medium on the substrates was observed with the AFM. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Radmacher, Manfred/A-3956-2012; Muller, Otto/K-6938-2012; Parak, Wolfgang J./M-3998-2014	Radmacher, Manfred/0000-0001-8744-4541; Muller, Otto/0000-0003-2241-3271; Parak, Wolfgang J./0000-0003-1672-6650												0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					367	379		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00145-4						WOS:000090030600008					
J	Rasmont, A; Leclere, P; Doneux, C; Lambin, G; Tong, JD; Jerome, R; Bredas, JL; Lazzaroni, R				Rasmont, A; Leclere, P; Doneux, C; Lambin, G; Tong, JD; Jerome, R; Bredas, JL; Lazzaroni, R			Microphase separation at the surface of block copolymers, as studied with atomic force microscopy	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												Atomic force microscopy (AFM) is used to study the phase separation process occurring in block copolymers in the solid state. The simultaneous measurement of the amplitude and the phase of the oscillating cantilever in the tapping mode operation provides the surface topography along with the cartography of the microdomains of different mechanical properties. This technique thus allows to characterize the size and shape of those microdomains and their organization at the surface (e.g. cubic lattice spheres, hexagonal lattice of cylinders, or lamellae). In this study, a series of symmetric triblock copolymers made of a inner elastomeric sequence (poly(butadiene) or poly(alkylacrylate)) and two outer thermoplastic sequences (poly(methylmethacrylate)) is analyzed by AFM in the tapping mode. The microphase separation and their morphology are essential factors for the potential of these materials as a new class of thermoplastic elastomers. Special attention is paid to the control of the surface morphology, as observed by AFM, by the molecular structure of the copolymers (volume ratio of the sequences, molecular weight, length of the alkyl side group) and the experimental conditions used for the sample preparation. The molecular structure of the chains is completely controlled by the synthesis, which relies on the sequential living anionic polymerization of the comonomers. The copolymers are analyzed as solvent-cast films, whose characteristics depend on the solvent used and the annealing conditions. The surface arrangement of the phase-separated elastomeric and thermoplastic microdomains observed on the AFM phase images is discussed on the basis of quantitative information provided by the statistical analysis by Fourier transform and grain size distribution calculations. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Bredas, Jean-Luc/A-3431-2008; LECLERE, Philippe/F-6768-2015	Bredas, Jean-Luc/0000-0001-7278-4471; LECLERE, Philippe/0000-0002-5490-0608												0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					381	395		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00146-6						WOS:000090030600009					
J	Bogdanovic, G; Meurk, A; Rutland, MW				Bogdanovic, G; Meurk, A; Rutland, MW			Tip friction - torsional spring constant determination	COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES												A non-destructive technique is presented for verifying torsional spring constants used in lateral force microscopy. Various calibrations of the microscope are required and these are detailed. The technique produces reasonable values which tend to be larger than those predicted from considerations of the cantilever dimensions. The differences are discussed in terms of length corrections and particularly the uncertainty in the thickness of the cantilevers, which has an enormous effect on the values obtained through a priori calculations. Methods for inferring the thickness are discussed. Further, artefacts in conventional force measurements related to the experiments performed here are discussed. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Rutland, Mark/F-8890-2012	Rutland, Mark/0000-0002-8935-8070												0927-7765					DEC 30	2000	19	4					397	405		10.1016/S0927-7765(00)00147-8						WOS:000090030600010					
J	Gardinier, A; Derenne, S; Robert, F; Behar, F; Largeau, C; Maquet, J				Gardinier, A; Derenne, S; Robert, F; Behar, F; Largeau, C; Maquet, J			Solid state CP/MAS C-13 NMR of the insoluble organic matter of the Orgueil and Murchison meteorites: quantitative study	EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE LETTERS												Solid state CP/MAS C-13 nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) study of the insoluble organic fraction isolated by HF/HCl treatment under an inert atmosphere from the Orgueil and Murchison carbonaceous meteorites is reported. Based on these spectra, eight different types of carbons (aro- and all-linked CH3, CH2, aliphatic C-linked to heteroelements, protonated and non-protonated aromatic C, carboxyls and carbonyls) were identified, their relative amounts were determined and theoretical NMR-derived H/C atomic ratios were calculated. Comparison of these H/C ratios with those obtained from elemental analysis revealed that a large part of the carbons of the insoluble fraction of both meteorites are not detected by CP/MAS C-13 NMR. Taking into account these undetected carbons, the relative abundance of aromatic carbons (as % of the total carbons) was calculated as between 69 and 78% in Orgueil and 61 and 67% in Murchison and thus shown to be much higher than previously thought. In addition, the NMR data allowed to calculate the ratio of non-protonated and protonated aromatic carbons. Based on previous studies on chemical and thermal degradation, the present NMR data were interpreted as reflecting the occurrence of highly substituted rather small aromatic moieties in these insoluble organic materials. Along with FTIR data, NMR results also pointed to a relatively high branching level in the aliphatic chains, especially for Murchison. According to the above results, the insoluble organic matter in these meteorites did not suffer a marked thermal maturation during the late hydrothermalism of the parent body. Its synthesis involved a statistical combination of all the possible bonds between -CH3, -CH2 and -CH radicals, producing both the aliphatic and the aromatic moieties. This model explains not only the chemical features of the chondritic insoluble organic material but also the typical FTIR signature of the interstellar medium. Therefore, organic material found in the interstellar medium and that incorporated in the most primitive objects of the solar system seem to share a common organosynthesis. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Derenne, Sylvie/I-9853-2014	Derenne, Sylvie/0000-0002-3446-9312												0012-821X	1385-013X				DEC 30	2000	184	1					9	21		10.1016/S0012-821X(00)00300-9						WOS:000166335500002					
J	Russell, SS; MacPherson, GJ; Leshin, LA; McKeegan, KD				Russell, SS; MacPherson, GJ; Leshin, LA; McKeegan, KD			O-16 enrichments in aluminum-rich chondrules from ordinary chondrites	EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE LETTERS												The oxygen isotopic compositions of seven Al-rich chondrules from four unequilibrated ordinary chondrites were measured in situ using an ion microprobe. On an oxygen three isotope plot, the data are continuous with the ordinary chondrite ferromagnesian chondrule field but extend it to more O-16-enriched values along a mixing line of slope = 0.83 +/- 0.09, with the lightest value recorded at delta O-18 = -15.7 +/- 1.8 parts per thousand and delta O-17 = -13.5 +/- 2.6 parts per thousand. If Al-rich chondrules were mixtures of ferromagnesian chondrules and CAI material, their bulk chemical compositions would require them to exhibit larger O-16 enrichments than we observe. Therefore, Al-rich chondrules are not simple mixtures of these two components. Three chondrules exhibit significant internal isotopic heterogeneity indicative of partial exchange with a gaseous reservoir. Porphyritic Al-rich chondrules are consistently O-16-rich relative to nonporphyritic ones, suggesting that degree of melting is a key factor and pointing to a nebular setting for the isotopic exchange process. Because Al-rich chondrules are closely related to ferromagnesian chondrules, their radiogenic Mg isotopic abundances can plausibly be applied to help constrain the timing or location of chondrule formation. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				UCLA, SIMS/A-1459-2011; McKeegan, Kevin/A-4107-2008	McKeegan, Kevin/0000-0002-1827-729X												0012-821X					DEC 30	2000	184	1					57	74		10.1016/S0012-821X(00)00309-5						WOS:000166335500005					
J	Eiler, JM; Gronvold, K; Kitchen, N				Eiler, JM; Gronvold, K; Kitchen, N			Oxygen isotope evidence for the origin of chemical variations in lavas from Theistareykir volcano in Iceland's northern volcanic zone	EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE LETTERS												Oxygen isotope ratios in phenocrysts from recent Theistareykir lavas (Iceland) are consistently O-18-depleted relative to common terrestrial basalts (e.g. delta O-18 olivine = 4.7-4.1 parts per thousand) and correlate with geochemical indices of 'enrichment' (e.g. K2O/TiO2; La/Sm) and major element indices of differentiation (e.g. Mg#; CaO/Na2O). The sense of these correlations is that decreasing delta O-18 is accompanied by increasing 'enriched' geochemical signatures and an increasing extent of differentiation. These trends are similar to (although more subtle than) those defined by highly differentiated and contaminated Icelandic andesites, dacites and rhyolites. The trends we observe are consistent with models in which primary recent Theistareykir magmas are highly 'depleted' in their incompatible element geochemistry and similar in delta O-18 to common terrestrial basalts; differentiation of these magmas is accompanied by contamination by the low delta O-18, and on average more 'enriched' rocks of the Icelandic crust to produce the observed spectrum in delta O-18 and other geochemical indices. Our results suggest that geochemical variations among recent Theistareykir lavas are only indirect constraints on the composition and dynamics of the Iceland plume. Extrapolation of the geochemical trends we observe to oxygen isotope compositions within the range of common oceanic basalts suggests that primary recent Theistareykir magmas are exceptionally depleted (e.g. La/Sm = 0.2-0.5), indicating unusually high degrees and/or multiple stages of melting of their sources. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0012-821X					DEC 30	2000	184	1					269	286		10.1016/S0012-821X(00)00318-6						WOS:000166335500020					
J	Aloisi, G; Pierre, C; Rouchy, JM; Foucher, JP; Woodside, J				Aloisi, G; Pierre, C; Rouchy, JM; Foucher, JP; Woodside, J		MEDINAUT Sci Party	Methane-related authigenic carbonates of eastern Mediterranean Sea mud volcanoes and their possible relation to gas hydrate destabilisation	EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCE LETTERS												Nautile submersible investigations of mud volcanoes and brine seep areas of the eastern Mediterranean Sea during the MEDINAUT cruise in November 1998 discovered extensive areas of authigenic carbonate crusts associated with methane emissions. Carbonate crusts form pavements, round slabs and circular mounds on the central, most active parts of mud volcanoes and in a fault-related valley where brines have accumulated to form a submarine brine lake. Authigenic carbonate nodules have been recovered from the same areas during the MEDINETH cruise in July 1999. Large C-13 depletions of authigenic calcite, aragonite and dolomite indicate methane as a major carbon source for the carbonate. Crust pavements are formed when methane from a freshly emplaced, methane-charged mud flow is oxidised at the seafloor. In this environment, where bottom waters provide the sulphate and magnesium, aragonite is favoured versus calcite and accounts for the majority of the methane-related authigenic carbonates. Calcite, when present, contains significant amounts of Mg2+ (high-Mg calcite), and possibly other divalent ions in its crystal lattice. In areas of brine seep and accumulation, dolomitic nodules are present at shallow depth in the sediment. The O-18 enrichment of the authigenic carbonates (up to 4 parts per thousand greater than calculated values for carbonates precipitating from modern eastern Mediterranean bottom waters) is interpreted as due to precipitation from O-18-rich fluids rather than as a temperature effect. The source of the O-18-rich fluids may be multiple and possibly includes the destabilisation of gas hydrates present at shallow subbottom depth, and the seepage of relic Messinian brines. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0012-821X					DEC 30	2000	184	1					321	338		10.1016/S0012-821X(00)00322-8						WOS:000166335500023					
J	Tachida, H				Tachida, H			DNA evolution under weak selection	GENE					Anton Dohrn Workshop on Neutralism and Selectionism - the End of a Debate	MAY 03-05, 2000	ISCHIA, ITALY	Int Soc Molec Evolut				Some DNA data show patterns of variation not expected under the neutral theory. Here, the independent multicodon (IMC) model, a nearly neutral mutation model assuming no interaction among codons, was studied when population size changes using computer simulation. Patterns of variation expected under the model were investigated using statistics for the neutrality tests. The average dispersion index is more than one when population size changes slowly but it never becomes large. The diversity at linked silent site decreases when the strength of selection is intermediate and the reduction is larger when population size changes slowly. Tajima's (1989. Genetics 123, 585-595) D is generally negative. Rejections by the Tajima's test occur more frequently if population size changes quickly but the effect of selection is confounded with the size change itself in this case. If we apply the test of McDonald and Kreitman (1991. Nature 351, 652-654), the rejection is always in the direction of excess replacement polymorphisms. The rejection probability decreases as the rate of population size changes decreases. These results show that the predictions of the IMC model are consistent with the pattern observed in mitochondrial DNA data but not consistent with some data of nuclear DNA. Interaction among codons or variable selection would be necessary to explain such cases. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0378-1119					DEC 30	2000	261	1					3	9		10.1016/S0378-1119(00)00475-3						WOS:000166759700002	11164031				
J	Rand, DM; Weinreich, DM; Cezairliyan, BO				Rand, DM; Weinreich, DM; Cezairliyan, BO			Neutrality tests of conservative-radical amino acid changes in nuclear- and mitochondrially-encoded proteins	GENE					Anton Dohrn Workshop on Neutralism and Selectionism - the End of a Debate	MAY 03-05, 2000	ISCHIA, ITALY	Int Soc Molec Evolut				The neutralist-selectionist debate should not be viewed as a dichotomy but as a continuum. While the strictly neutral model suggests a neutralist-selectionist dichotomy, the nearly neutral model is a continuous model spanning strict neutrality through weak selection (Ns similar to 1) to deterministic selection (Ns > 3). We illustrate these points with polymorphism and divergence data from a sample of 73 genes (31 mitochondrial, 36 nuclear genes from Drosophila, and six Arabidopsis data sets). In an earlier study we used the McDonald-Kreitman (MK) test to show that amino acid replacement polymorphism in animal mitochondrial genes and Arabidopsis genes show a consistent trend toward negative selection, whereas nuclear genes from Drosophila span a range from negative selection, through neutrality, to positive selection. Here we analyze a subset of these genes (13 Drosophila nuclear, ten mitochondrial, and six Arabidopsis nuclear) for polymorphism and divergence of conservative and radical amino acid replacements (a protein-based conservative-radical MK, or pMK, test). The distinct patterns of selection between the different genomes is not apparent with the pMK test. Different definitions of conservative and radical (based on amino acid polarity volume or charge) give inconsistent results across genes. We suggest that segregating fitness difference between silent and replacement mutations are more visible to selections than are segregating fitness differences between conservative and radical amino acid and replacement mutations are more visible to selection than are segregating fitness differences between conservative and radical amino acid mutations. New data on the variation among genes with different opportunities for positive and negative selection are as important to the continuum view of the neutralist-selectionist debate as is the distribution of selection coefficients within individual genes. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0378-1119					DEC 30	2000	261	1					115	125		10.1016/S0378-1119(00)00483-2						WOS:000166759700014	11164043				
J	Korkmaz, KS; Korkmaz, CG; Ragnhildstveit, E; Kizildag, S; Pretlow, TG; Saatcioglu, F				Korkmaz, KS; Korkmaz, CG; Ragnhildstveit, E; Kizildag, S; Pretlow, TG; Saatcioglu, F			Full-length cDNA sequence and genomic organization of human NKX3A - alternative forms and regulation by both androgens and estrogens	GENE												NKX3A (NKX3.1) is a recently identified androgen-regulated gene that is largely specific to prostate for expression and likely to code for a homeobox protein. Here we report the full-length mRNA and genomic organization of human NKX3.1. There are at least five different splice variants of NKX3.1 mRNA that result in different open reading frames (ORFs). There is extensive similarity between the human and the mouse NKX3.1 cDNA sequences outside of the ORFs (greater than 60% overall identity), which may be involved in modulating NKX3.1 expression. In addition to its androgen regulation in the prostate cancer cell line LNCaP, we show that NKX3.1 expression is androgen-dependent in the CWR22 prostate cancer xenograft model. Interestingly, NKX3.1 is highly expressed in the androgen-independent derivative CWR22R in the absence of androgens, indicating that it may be deregulated in advanced prostate cancer. Using a Green Flourescent Protein fusion construct, we show that NKX3.1 is a nuclear protein consistent with its proposed function as a homeobox transcription factor. Furthermore, in addition to androgens, NKX3.1 expression is up-regulated by 17 beta -estradiol, but not by progesterone, dexamethasone, or 3,5,3'-triiodothyronine in LNCaP cells. Regulation of NKX3.1 by androgens and 17 beta -estradiol in prostate cancer cells and its deregulation in androgen-independent prostate cancer suggest that it may have important regulatory roles during prostate cancer progression. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0378-1119					DEC 30	2000	260	1-2					25	36		10.1016/S0378-1119(00)00453-4						WOS:000166141200003	11137288				
J	Ohno, K; Takahashi, Y; Hirose, F; Inoue, YH; Taguchi, O; Nishida, Y; Matsukage, A; Yamaguchi, M				Ohno, K; Takahashi, Y; Hirose, F; Inoue, YH; Taguchi, O; Nishida, Y; Matsukage, A; Yamaguchi, M			Characterization of a Drosophila homologue of the human myelodysplasia/myeloid leukemia factor (MLF)	GENE												The transcription factor DREF regulates proliferation-related genes in Drosophila. With two-hybrid screening using DREF as a bait, we have obtained a clone encoding a protein homologous to human myelodysplasia/myeloid leukemia factor 1 (hMLF1). We termed the protein Drosophila MLF (dMLF); it consists of a polypeptide of 309 amino acid residues, whose sequence shares 23.1% identity with hMLF1. High conservation of 54.2% identity over 107 amino acids was found in the central region. The dMLF gene was mapped to 52D on the second chromosome by in situ hybridization. Interaction between dMLF and DREF in vitro could be confirmed by glutathione S-transferase pull-down assay, with the conserved central region appearing to play an important role in this. Northern blot hybridization analysis revealed dMLF mRNA levels to be high in unfertilized eggs, early embryos, pupae and adult males, and relatively low in adult females and larvae. This fluctuation of mRNA during Drosophila development is similar to that observed for DREF mRNA, except in the pupa and adult male. Using a specific antibody against the dMLF, we performed immunofluorescent staining of Drosophila Kc cells and showed a primarily cytoplasmic staining, whereas DREF localizes in the nucleus. However, dMLF protein contains a putative 14-3-3 binding motif involved in the subcellular localization of various regulatory molecules, and interaction with DREF could be regulated through this motif. The transgenic fly data suggesting the genetic interaction between DREF and dMLF support this possibility. Characterization of dMLF in the present study provides the molecular basis for analysis of its significance in Drosophila. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0378-1119					DEC 30	2000	260	1-2					133	143		10.1016/S0378-1119(00)00447-9						WOS:000166141200014	11137299				
J	Dorendorf, F; Churikova, T; Koloskov, A; Worner, G				Dorendorf, F; Churikova, T; Koloskov, A; Worner, G			Late Pleistocene to Holocene activity at Bakening volcano and surrounding monogenetic centers (Kamchatka): volcanic geology and geochemical evolution	JOURNAL OF VOLCANOLOGY AND GEOTHERMAL RESEARCH												The different roles of variable mantle sources and intra-crustal differentiation processes at Bakening volcano (Kamchatka) and contemporaneous basaltic monogenetic centers are studied using major and trace elements and isotopic data. Three suites of volcanic activity are recognized: (1) plateau basalts of Lower Pleistocene age; (2) andesites and dacites of the Bakening volcano, the New Bakening volcano dacitic centers nearby; and (3) contemporaneous basaltic cinder cones erupted along subduction zone--parallel N-S faults. Age-data show that the last eruptions in the Bakening area occurred only 600-1200 years ago, suggesting the volcano is potentially active. Major element variations and petrographic observations provides evidence for a fractionation assemblage of olivine, clinopyroxene, +/-plagioclase, +/-magnetite (?) within the basaltic suite. The fractionation in the andesites and dacites is dominated by amphibole, clinopyroxene. orthopyroxene and plagioclase plus minor amounts of magnetite and apatite. The youngest cpx-opx-andesites of Bakening main volcano deviate from that trend. Their source was probably formed by mixing of basaltic magmas into the silicic magma chamber of the Bakening volcano. Overall trace element patterns as well as the Sr-Nd-Pb isotopic compositions are quite similar in all rocks despite large differences in their chemical composition (from basalt to rhyodacite). In detail however, the andesite-dacites of the central Bakening volcano show a stronger enrichment in the more incompatible elements and depletion in HREE compared to the monogenetic basaltic centers. This results in a crossing of the REE-pattern for the two suites. The decrease in the HREEs can be explained by amphibole fractionation. A slab component is less likely because it would result in fractionation of the HREE from each other, which is not observed. The higher relative amounts of LILE in the dacitic and the large scatter in the basaltic rocks must be the result of a variable source enrichment by slab-derived fluids overprinting a variable depleted mantle wedge. The plateau basalts are less depleted in HFSE and show a more fractionated HREE pattern. These lavas could either result from a slab component or the addition of an OIB-type enriched mantle in their source. (C) 2000 EIsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.					Churikova, Tatiana/0000-0002-9929-9764												0377-0273					DEC 30	2000	104	1-4					131	151		10.1016/S0377-0273(00)00203-1						WOS:000166971200008					
J	Reddy, ASN; Reddy, VS; Golovkin, M				Reddy, ASN; Reddy, VS; Golovkin, M			A calmodulin binding protein from Arabidopsis is induced by ethylene and contains a DNA-binding motif	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												Calmodulin (CaM), a keg calcium sensor in all eukaryotes, regulates diverse cellular processes by interacting with other proteins. To isolate CaM binding proteins involved in ethylene signal transduction, we screened an expression library prepared from ethylene-treated Arabidopsis seedlings with S-35-labeled CaM. A cDNA clone, EICBP (Ethylene-Induced CaM Binding Protein), encoding a protein that interacts with activated CaM was isolated in this screening. The CaM: binding domain in EICBP was mapped to the C-terminus of the protein. These results indicate that calcium, through CaM, could regulate the activity of EICBP. The EICBP is expressed in different tissues and its expression in seedlings is induced by ethylene. The EICBP contains, in addition to a CaM binding domain, several features that are typical of transcription factors. These include a DNA-binding domain at the N terminus, an acidic region at the C terminus, and nuclear localization signals. In database searches a partial cDNA (CG-1) encoding a DNA-binding motif from parsley and an ethylene up-regulated partial cDNA from tomato (ER66) showed significant similarity to EICBP. In addition, five hypothetical proteins in the Arabidopsis genome also showed a very high sequence similarity with EICBP, indicating that there are several EICBP-related proteins in Arabidopsis. The structural features of EICBP are conserved in all EICBP-related proteins in Arabidopsis, suggesting that they may constitute a new family of DNA binding proteins and are Likely to be involved in modulating gene expression in the presence of ethylene. (C) 2000 Academic Press.																	0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					762	769		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4032						WOS:000166385900005	11162426				
J	Bjorkhaug, L; Ye, HG; Horikawa, Y; Sovik, O; Molven, A; Njolstad, PR				Bjorkhaug, L; Ye, HG; Horikawa, Y; Sovik, O; Molven, A; Njolstad, PR			MODY associated with two novel hepatocyte nuclear factor-1 alpha loss-of-function mutations (P112L and Q466X)	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												Maturity-onset diabetes of the young (MODY) is an autosomal dominant form of diabetes characterized by early onset of pancreatic dysfunction. MODY type 3 is caused by mutations in the hepatocyte nuclear factor (HNF)-1 alpha. During a screening of Norwegian patients with suspected MODY we identified two novel HNF-1 alpha mutations, P112L and Q466X. The molecular mechanisms underlying the disease were studied by analyzing the DNA binding properties, transcriptional activation, and subcellular localization of HNF-1 alpha P112L and Q466X compared to wild type HNF-1 alpha. P112L had reduced ability to bind an HNF1 consensus sequence and to activate transcription. Q486X did not differ from wild type HNF-1 alpha in DNA binding activity. Transactivation, however, was markedly reduced. When both mutants were coexpressed with wild type HNF-1 alpha in HeLa cells, transcriptional activity appeared unaffected, suggesting that a dominant-negative mechanism was not present. Immunolocalization experiments showed that P112L HNF-1 alpha was correctly targeted to nuclei in HeLa cells. In contrast, some Q466X HNF-1 alpha protein was retained in the cytoplasm, which indicated that the mechanism for nuclear localization was disturbed. Thus, the HNF-1 alpha mutations P112L and Q466X both seem to impair pancreatic p cell function by loss of-function mechanisms; P112L by reduced DNA binding and reduced ability to transactivate, and Q466X by reduced transactivation and incomplete nuclear targeting. (C) 2000 Academic Press.					Gundersen, Lise Bjorkhaug/0000-0002-9695-4559												0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					792	798		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4024						WOS:000166385900009	11162430				
J	Inoue, S; Ogawa, S; Horie, K; Hoshino, S; Goto, W; Hosoi, T; Tsutsumi, O; Muramatsu, M; Ouchi, Y				Inoue, S; Ogawa, S; Horie, K; Hoshino, S; Goto, W; Hosoi, T; Tsutsumi, O; Muramatsu, M; Ouchi, Y			An estrogen receptor beta isoform that lacks exon 5 has dominant negative activity on both ER alpha and ER beta	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												An alternatively spliced isoform of human estrogen receptor beta (ER beta) has been isolated from normal human testis mRNA that is coexpressed with wild-type ERP by reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). Sequence analysis of the ER beta isoform PCR product reveals the absence of 139 bp that corresponds to the entire exon 5 of wild-type ER beta, which predicts 60 lack part of the hormone-binding domain, The transient expression of the exon 5-deleted isoform of ERP (ERP beta Delta5) had no effect on basal transactivation activity of an estrogen-responsive luciferase reporter gene. This finding was in contrast to the previous reports that the exon 8-deleted isoform of ER alpha (ER alpha Delta5) acts as a dominant positive receptor, increasing basal gene transactivation itself. Moreover, when ER beta Delta5 was cotransfected with the wild-type ER alpha or ER beta, it behaved as a dominant negative receptor that inhibited not only estradiol-stimulated transactivation by ER beta but also that by ER alpha. The ligand-independent nuclear localization of ER beta Delta5 was confirmed by immunohistochemistry, and the coexpression of the isoform and the wild-type receptors could be observed in a single cell that transfected with both receptor cDNAs, These findings indicate that ER beta Delta5 has a potential as a dominant negative receptor that blocks both ER alpha and ER beta signaling pathways, suggesting some physiological roles of this isoform as an "ER inhibitor''. (C) 2000 Academic Press.																	0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					814	819		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4010						WOS:000166385900013	11162434				
J	Marques, F; Moreau, JL; Peaucellier, G; Lozano, JC; Schatt, P; Picard, A; Callebaut, I; Perret, E; Geneviere, AM				Marques, F; Moreau, JL; Peaucellier, G; Lozano, JC; Schatt, P; Picard, A; Callebaut, I; Perret, E; Geneviere, AM			A new subfamily of high molecular mass CDC2-related kinases with PITAI/VRE motifs	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												Kinases of the CDCS family play a key role in cell cycle regulation and gene expression. In the present work, we identified sea urchin and human cDNAs encoding homologues of a high molecular mass CDC2-like kinase (designated CDC2L5) sharing respectively a PITAVRE and PITAIRE motif. The human cDNA encodes the full-length amino acid sequence of the Cholinesterase-related cell division controller (CHED) kinase, a previously published partial coding sequence. CDC2L5 overexpressed in mammalian cells is a approximate to 170-kDa nuclear protein, The mRNA is present during the sea urchin early embryogenesis and is ubiquitously expressed in human tissues. (C) 2000 Academic Press.				Geneviere, Anne-Marie/A-3942-2013													0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					832	837		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4042						WOS:000166385900015	11162436				
J	Harish, S; Ashok, MS; Khanam, T; Rangarajan, PN				Harish, S; Ashok, MS; Khanam, T; Rangarajan, PN			Serine 27, a human Retinoid X Receptor alpha residue, phosphorylated by protein kinase A is essential for CyclicAMP-mediated downregulation of RXR alpha function	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												Retinoid X Receptor alpha (RXR alpha), a member of the steroid-thyroid hormone receptor super family, is phosphorylated in vitro by protein kinase A (PKA) and this phosphorylation is inhibited in presence of PKA inhibitory peptide. Analysis of various deletion mutants of RXR alpha indicate that the amino-terminal A/B domain is the target for PKA phosphorylation. An RXR alpha mutant in which serine residue 27 is mutated to alanine is no longer phosphorylated by PKA. In vivo transfection experiments in COS cells indicate that cyclicAMP represses retinoic acid-mediated transcriptional activation of RXR alpha and this repression is mediated by serine 27. These results indicate that serine 27 of RXR alpha is an unique target for phosphorylation by PKA in vitro and it has an important role in the crosstalk between RXR alpha and cyclicAMP signalling pathways. (C) 2000 Academic Press.				Rangarajan, Pundi/A-7365-2009	Rangarajan, Pundi/0000-0002-6536-9891												0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					853	857		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4043						WOS:000166385900018	11162439				
J	Ibuki, Y; Goto, R				Ibuki, Y; Goto, R			Suppression of apoptosis by UVB irradiation: Survival signaling via P13-kinase/Akt pathway	BIOCHEMICAL AND BIOPHYSICAL RESEARCH COMMUNICATIONS												UVB irradiation induces apoptosis in several cell types. However, me report here that UVB irradiation prevents induction of apoptosis in cells detached from the extracellular matrix under serum-free conditions. NIH3T3 cells cultured in bovine serum albumin-coated dishes (detached from the extracellular matrix) underwent apoptosis under serum-free conditions, which was inhibited by UVB (<0.1 J/cm(2)) irradiation, keeping suspension conditions, as determined by chromatin condensation and the appearance of a subG1 DNA fraction. Furthermore, UVB irradiation decreased caspase-3/7, -8/6, and -9 activation and eliminated loss of mitochondrial inner transmembrane potential, suggesting suppression upstream of the caspase cascade. Treatment with PI3-kinase inhibitors, wortmannin, and LY294002 partly eliminated the UV-mediated inhibition of cell death and recovered the inhibited caspase-3/7 activity. Phosphorylation of Akt was observed from 15 min after UVB irradiation. These results suggested that UVB irradiation transduced a survival signal via PI3 kinase activation and phosphorylation of Akt, and induced some apoptosis inhibition factors upstream of the caspase cascade. (C) 2000 Academic Press.																	0006-291X					DEC 29	2000	279	3					872	878		10.1006/bbrc.2000.4018						WOS:000166385900021	11162442				
J	Bryan, PN				Bryan, PN			Protein engineering of subtilisin	BIOCHIMICA ET BIOPHYSICA ACTA-PROTEIN STRUCTURE AND MOLECULAR ENZYMOLOGY												The serine protease subtilisin is an important industrial enzyme as well as a model for understanding the enormous rate enhancements affected by enzymes. For these reasons along with the timely cloning of the gene, ease of expression and purification and availability of atomic resolution structures, subtilisin became a model system for protein engineering studies in the 1980s. Fifteen years later, mutations in well over 50% of the 275 amino acids of subtilisin have been reported in the scientific literature. Most subtilisin engineering has involved catalytic amino acids, substrate binding regions and stabilizing mutations. Stability has been the property of subtilisin which has been most amenable to enhancement, yet perhaps least understood. This review will give a brief overview of the subtilisin engineering field, critically review what has been learned about subtilisin stability from protein engineering experiments and conclude with some speculation about the prospects for future subtilisin engineering. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0167-4838					DEC 29	2000	1543	2			SI		203	222		10.1016/S0167-4838(00)00235-1						WOS:000166500900002	11150607				
J	van der Veen, BA; Uitdehaag, JCM; Dijkstra, BW; Dijkhuizen, L				van der Veen, BA; Uitdehaag, JCM; Dijkstra, BW; Dijkhuizen, L			Engineering of cyclodextrin glycosyltransferase reaction and product specificity	BIOCHIMICA ET BIOPHYSICA ACTA-PROTEIN STRUCTURE AND MOLECULAR ENZYMOLOGY																Dijkhuizen, Lubbert/E-9454-2014													0167-4838					DEC 29	2000	1543	2			SI		336	360		10.1016/S0167-4838(00)00233-8						WOS:000166500900008					
J	Gavini, G; Zanelli, SA; Ashraf, QM; Mishra, OP; Delivoria-Papadopoulos, M				Gavini, G; Zanelli, SA; Ashraf, QM; Mishra, OP; Delivoria-Papadopoulos, M			Effect of nitric oxide synthase inhibition on high affinity Ca2+-ATPase during hypoxia in cerebral cortical neuronal nuclei of newborn piglets	BRAIN RESEARCH												Previous studies have shown that during hypoxia, neuronal nuclear high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity is increased in the cerebral cortex of newborn piglets. The present study tests the hypothesis that pretreatment with N-nitro-L-arginine (NNLA) will prevent the hypoxia-induced increase in high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity in cortical neuronal nuclear membrane of newborn piglets. We also tested the hypothesis that nitration is a mechanism of elevation of the high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity during hypoxia. Studies were performed in Rye normoxic, five hypoxic, and six NNLA-pretreated (40 mg/kg) hypoxic newborn piglets. Cerebral cortical neuronal nuclei were isolated and the high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity was determined. Further, normoxic samples were aliquoted into two sub-groups for in vitro nitration with 0.5 mM peroxynitrite and subsequent determination of the high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity. The activity increased from 309+/-40 nmol Pi/mg protein/h in the normoxic group to 520+/-108 nmol Pi/mg protein/h in the hypoxic group (P<0.05). In the NNLA-pretreated group, the activity was 442+/-53 nmol Pi/mg protein/h (P<0.05), which is 25% lower than in the hypoxic group. Tn the nitrated group the enzyme activity increased to 554+/-59 nmol Pi/mg protein/h (P<0.05). Thus peroxynitrire-induced nitration in vitro increased the high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity and NNLA administration in vivo partially prevented the hypoxia induced increase in neuronal nuclear high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity. We conclude that the hypoxia-induced increase in nuclear membrane high affinity Ca2+-ATPase activity is NO-mediated and that nitration of the enzyme is a mechanism of its modification. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0006-8993					DEC 29	2000	887	2					385	390		10.1016/S0006-8993(00)03069-9						WOS:000166116900017	11134628				
J	Smalheiser, NR; Collins, BJ				Smalheiser, NR; Collins, BJ			Coordinate enrichment of cranin (dystroglycan) subunits in synaptic membranes of sheep brain	BRAIN RESEARCH												Cranin (dystroglycan), a mucin-like extracellular matrix receptor comprised of two subunits (alpha and beta), is involved in regulating cell-matrix interactions in a variety of tissues, including brain. A basic issue remains unresolved concerning the distribution of cranin in brain: are the alpha and beta subunits coordinately expressed at the synapse? We report here that cranin is indeed enriched progressively in synaptosomes and synaptic membranes of sheep brain, as assessed by immunoblotting and laminin-blotting assays, and that the extent of enrichment is similar for both alpha and beta subunits. These findings support the hypothesis that cranin (dystroglycan) contributes to synaptic function in the CNS. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science BN. All rights reserved.					Smalheiser, Neil/0000-0003-1079-3406												0006-8993					DEC 29	2000	887	2					469	471		10.1016/S0006-8993(00)03040-7						WOS:000166116900033	11134644				
J	Hyde, LA; Sherman, GF; Stavnezer, AJ; Denenberg, VH				Hyde, LA; Sherman, GF; Stavnezer, AJ; Denenberg, VH			The effects of neocortical ectopias on Lashley III water maze learning in New Zealand Black mice	BRAIN RESEARCH																													0006-8993					DEC 29	2000	887	2					482	483		10.1016/S0006-8993(00)03062-6						WOS:000166116900036	11134647				
J	Baloght, SA; Waters, NS; Hyde, LA; McDowell, CS; Casler, CM; Denenberg, VH				Baloght, SA; Waters, NS; Hyde, LA; McDowell, CS; Casler, CM; Denenberg, VH			Avoidance learning in autoimmune mice	BRAIN RESEARCH												Previous studies have shown that autoimmune mice perform very poorly on active avoidance learning tasks. In the current studies, mice with lupus-like systemic autoimmunity were able to learn active, as well as passive, avoidance protocols with shock as reinforcement. Therefore, the behavioral deficits seen in active avoidance tasks are not a consequence of the use of electric shock. Rather, the current findings suggest that the inability of autoimmune mice to learn shock motivated responding is due to multiple performance factors, including shock level and properties of the testing apparatus. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0006-8993					DEC 29	2000	887	2					484	487		10.1016/S0006-8993(00)03064-X						WOS:000166116900037	11134648				
J	Vila, A; Mosquera, RA				Vila, A; Mosquera, RA			A comparative AIM study of alkyl monoethers and their protonated forms	CHEMICAL PHYSICS LETTERS												The effects of the protonation on the atomic and bond properties of the oxygen atom were studied in a series of unbranched alkyl monoethers of formula CH3(CH2)(n)O(CH2)(m)CH3 (n, m = 0, 1,2, 3,4) using MP2/6-31 ++G**//MP2/6-31G*' wave functions. The different character of oxygen in methylethers and the remaining dialkylethers and the charge transfer dominant part in the protonation process are supported by two different linear correlations tone for methoxyethers and another for the remaining ethers) between proton charges and protonation energies. The atomic energy of the proton accounts for more than 93% of the protonation energy. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0009-2614	1873-4448				DEC 29	2000	332	5-6					474	480		10.1016/S0009-2614(00)01323-3						WOS:000166235900009					
J	Puka-Sundvall, M; Gajkowska, B; Cholewinski, M; Blomgren, K; Lazarewicz, JW; Hagberg, H				Puka-Sundvall, M; Gajkowska, B; Cholewinski, M; Blomgren, K; Lazarewicz, JW; Hagberg, H			Subcellular distribution of calcium and ultrastructural changes after cerebral hypoxia-ischemia in immature rats	DEVELOPMENTAL BRAIN RESEARCH												Recent data imply that mitochondrial regulation of calcium is critical in the process leading to hypoxic-ischemic brain injury. The aim was to study the subcellular distribution of calcium in correlation with ultrastructural changes after hypoxia-ischemia in neonatal rats. Seven-day-old rats were subjected to permanent unilateral carotid artery ligation and exposure to hypoxia (7.7% oxygen in nitrogen) for 90 min. Animals were perfusion-fixed after 30 min, 3 h or 24 h of reperfusion. Sections were sampled for light microscopy and electron microscopy combined with the oxalate-pyroantimonate technique. At 30 min and 3 h of reflow, 3 progressive accumulation of calcium was detected in the endoplasmic reticulum, cytoplasm, nucleus and, most markedly, in the mitochondrial matrix of neurons in the gray matter in the core area of injury. Some mitochondria developed a considerable degree of swelling reaching a diameter of several mum at 3 h of reflow whereas the majority of mitochondria appeared moderately affected. Chromatin condensation was observed in nuclei of many cells with severely swollen mitochondria with calcium deposits. A whole spectrum of morphological features ranging from necrosis to apoptosis was seen in degenerating cells. After 24 h, there was extensive injury in the cerebral cortex as judged by breaks of mitochondrial and plasma membranes, and a general decrease of cellular electron density. In the white matter of the core area of injury, the axonal elements exhibited varicosity-like swellings filled with calcium-pyroantimonate deposits. Furthermore, the thin myelin sheaths were loaded with calcium. Numerous oligodendroglia-like cells displayed apoptotic morphology 'with shrunken cytoplasm and chromatin condensation, whereas astroglial necrosis was not seen. In conclusion, markedly swollen 'giant' mitochondria with large amounts of calcium were found at 3 h of reperfusion often in neuronal cells with condensation of the nuclear chromatin. The results are discussed in relation to mitochondrial permeability transition and activation of apoptotic processes. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.																	0165-3806					DEC 29	2000	125	1-2					31	41		10.1016/S0165-3806(00)00110-3						WOS:000166692800004					
J	Diaz, S; Martin-Gonzalez, A; Borniquel, S; Gutierrez, JC				Diaz, S; Martin-Gonzalez, A; Borniquel, S; Gutierrez, JC			Cyrtolophosis elongata (Colpodea, Ciliophora): Some aspects of ciliary pattern, division, cortical and nuclear changes during encystment and resting cyst ultrastructure	EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF PROTISTOLOGY												Cyrtolophosis elongata is a small soil ciliate of the order Cyrtolophosidida, class Colpodea. Using the silver carbonate method we have been able to study the ciliary pattern of vegetative and dividing cells. Transmission electron microscopy revealed that there is no micro-macronuclear complex in this species. This type of nuclear apparatus thus cannot be considered as most important apomorphy of the Cyrtolophosidida. Division is in the swimming condition, stomatogenesis is pleurotelokinetal. Feulgen stain indicates the absence of a macronuclear chromatin extrusion process during both division and encystment. Cortical and cytoplasmic phenomena during encystment are similar to those of Colpoda spp. These data and ultrastructural observations of mature resting cysts indicate that Cyrtolophosis elongata has resting cysts of PKR (Partial-kinetosome-resorbing) type, with a cyst wall composed by two layers.																	0932-4739					DEC 29	2000	36	4					367	378								WOS:000167342300002					
J	Nilsson, JR				Nilsson, JR			On macronuclear "subnuclei", or genome segregation, and "Amitosis" in amicronucleate Tetrahymena pyriformis GL. A study utilizing the effect of vanadate on nuclear division	EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF PROTISTOLOGY												In 1940, Tetrahymena pyriformis GL was reported amicronucleate by W. H. Furgason. Unable to renew its genetic complement through conjugation, the ciliate still thrives with unchanged phenotype. This fact indicates physical integrity of the haploid macronuclear genome (5 "chromosomes") during cell division, as also reflected in 90 unit-sized chromatin aggregates ("subnuclei") distributed equally to the daughters. This stands in contrast to biochemical sizing of bulk macronuclear DNA in thousands of subchromosomal DNA fragments distributed randomly during cell division. The purpose was to investigate the problem utilizing vanadate that affects nuclear division so that the daughters may receive anything from the entire G(2)-nucleus to no nucleus at all [39]; in theory a single aggregate suffices to survive. Single cell cultures of daughters, derived from cells divided in vanadate, revealed survival of all, but not anucleate, daughters and progeny of unchanged phenotype, hence indicating that the macronuclear chromatin aggregates contain full genetic complement. "Amitosis" in Tetrahymena is genome segregation but equal karyokinesis depends on correct positioning of the macronucleus, properly related to its anterior and posterior movements prior to elongation as though it becomes anchored to both cell poles. Vanadate disturbed correct positioning of the nucleus.																	0932-4739					DEC 29	2000	36	4					423	436								WOS:000167342300008					
J	Mariotti, M; Manganini, M; Maier, JAM				Mariotti, M; Manganini, M; Maier, JAM			Modulation of WHSC2 expression in human endothelial cells	FEBS LETTERS												WHSC2, a novel gene recently isolated within the critical region of Wolf-Hirschhorn syndrome, is expressed in endothelial cells. WHSC2 is downregulated by HIV-1 Tat, whereas it is not modulated by angiogenic and pro-differentiative molecules. WHSC2 encodes a basic polypeptide of 528 amino acids. The in vitro translated protein shows a molecular weight of 57 kDa. WHSC2 has two nuclear translocation sequences which actively mediate its transport to the nucleus, as shown in whsc2-GFP-transfected NIH-3T3, We also found a helix-loop-helix (HLH) motif in region 130-185, Since members of the HLH family control differentiation and cell cycle progression, we hypothesize that WHSC2 may function as a transcriptional repressor. (C) 2000 Federation of European Biochemical Societies. Published by Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.					Maier, Jeanette Anne Marie/0000-0002-6326-9221												0014-5793					DEC 29	2000	487	2					166	170		10.1016/S0014-5793(00)02335-8						WOS:000166388400005	11150502				
J	Giordano, A; Nisoli, E; Tonello, C; Cancello, R; Carruba, MO; Cinti, S				Giordano, A; Nisoli, E; Tonello, C; Cancello, R; Carruba, MO; Cinti, S			Expression and distribution of heme oxygenase-1 and-2 in rat brown adipose tissue: The modulatory role of the noradrenergic system	FEBS LETTERS												To investigate whether brown adipose tissue (BAT) expresses the inducible (HO-1) and the constitutive (HO-2) isoform of heme oxygenase, reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction, Western blotting and immunohistochemistry were performed on interscapular BAT (IBAT) from rats acclimated at environmental temperature or exposed to cold. Both HO isoforms were detected in rat IBAT. They were immunolocalized in the cytoplasm and/or nuclei of brown adipocytes, in parenchymal capillaries, arteries and in some veins and nerves. Whereas cold exposure did not affect HO-2 expression, it significantly increased the expression of HO-1, both at mRNA (about 3-fold) and protein (about 2-fold) levels, reflecting the increased expression of HO-1 in the brown adipotytes and endothelial cells of parenchymal capillaries. Western blotting of cytosolic and nuclear protein extracts from cultured differentiated brown adipocytes showed that HO-1 and HO-2 are indeed localized in the cytosol and nuclei of brown adipocytes; and that noradrenaline stimulation significantly increased their amount in cytosol but not in the nuclear fraction. (C) 2000 Federation of European Biochemical Societies. Published by Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.				Nisoli, Enzo/D-6526-2014	Nisoli, Enzo/0000-0002-6670-1630												0014-5793					DEC 29	2000	487	2					171	175		10.1016/S0014-5793(00)02217-1						WOS:000166388400006	11150503				
J	Boulyga, SF; Becker, JS; Matusevitch, JL; Dietze, HJ				Boulyga, SF; Becker, JS; Matusevitch, JL; Dietze, HJ			Isotope ratio measurements of spent reactor uranium in environmental samples by using inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry	INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY												As a result of the accident at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant (NPP) the environment was contaminated with spent nuclear fuel. The U-236 isotope was used in this study to monitor the spent uranium from nuclear fallout in soil samples collected in the vicinity of the Chernobyl NPP. A rapid and sensitive analytical procedure for uranium isotopic ratio measurement in environmental samples based on inductively coupled plasma quadrupole mass spectrometry with a hexapole collision cell (HEX-ICP-QMS) was developed. Figures of merit for the HEX-ICP-QMS were studied with a plasma-shielded torch using different nebulizers [such as an ultrasonic nebulizer (USN) and a Meinhard nebulizer] for the solution introduction. An U-238(+) ion intensity of up to 27 000 MHz/ppm in HEX-ICP-QMS with USN was observed by introducing helium into the hexapole collision cell as the collision gas at a how rate of 10 mL min(-1). The formation rate of uranium hydride ions UH+/U+ of 2 x 10(-6) was obtained by using USN with a membrane desolvator. The detection limit for U-236 in 10 mug L-1 uranium solution was 3 pg L-1 corresponding to the limit of U-236/U-238 ratio determination of 3 x 10(-7). in the case of low isotopic abundance of U-236 (<10(-5)). the measured isotopic ratio in the synthetic mixture was systematically lower than the calculated ratio. The precision of uranium isotopic ratio measurements in 10 <mu>g L-l laboratory uranium isotopic standard solution was 0.13% (U-235/U-238) and 0.33% (U-236/U-238) using a Meinhard nebulizer and 0.45% (U-235/U-238) and 0.88% (U-236/U-238) using an USN. The isotopic composition of all investigated Chernobyl soil samples differed from those of natural uranium: i.e. in these samples the U-236/U-238 ratio ranged from 10(-5) to 10(-3). Results of isotopic ratio measurement by HEX-ICP-QMS in soil samples are in agreement with those obtained by using a double-focusing sector field ICP-MS within experimental errors.(C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V.																	1387-3806					DEC 29	2000	203	1-3					143	154		10.1016/S1387-3806(00)00296-7						WOS:000166338100013					
J	Alvarez, R; Evans, LA; Milham, P; Wilson, MA				Alvarez, R; Evans, LA; Milham, P; Wilson, MA			Analysis of oxygen-18 in orthophosphate by electrospray ionisation mass spectrometry	INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY												Isotope distributions in phosphate are useful measurements in geochemical systems since they give information on origin and environmental oxygen exchange processes. It is often necessary to perform measurements rapidly at the parts per million level on milligram quantities of sample. However, current methodologies require conversion to gas and/or time consuming multiple precipitation steps or insensitive nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) techniques. in the electrospray method developed here, lengthy analyses requiring precipitation of phosphate are unnecessary. Moreover, there is no requirement for conversion to a simple gas and indirect evaluation. Accuracy is demonstrated by good agreement with NMR measurements on concentrated laboratory prepared chemical solutions. After dilution, electrospray analyses gave similar results. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V.																	1387-3806					DEC 29	2000	203	1-3					177	186		10.1016/S1387-3806(00)00297-9						WOS:000166338100016					
J	Guzey, M; Takayama, S; Reed, JC				Guzey, M; Takayama, S; Reed, JC			BAG1L enhances trans-activation function of the vitamin D receptor	JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY												The vitamin D receptor (VDR) is a member of the steroid/retinoid receptor superfamily of nuclear receptors that has potential tumor-suppressive functions. We show here that VDR interacts with and is regulated by BAG1L, a nuclear protein that binds heat shock 70-kDa (Hsp70) family molecular chaperones. Endogenous BAG1L can be eo-immunoprecipitated with VDR from prostate cancer cells (ALVA31; LNCaP) in a ligand-dependent manner. BAG1L, but not shorter non-nuclear isoforms of this protein (BAG1; BAG1M/Rap46), markedly enhanced, in a ligand-dependent manner, the ability of VDR to trans-activate reporter gene plasmids containing a vitamin D response element in transient transfection assays. Mutant BAG1L lacking the C-terminal Hsc70-binding domain suppressed tin a concentration-dependent fashion) VDR-mediated trans-activation of vitamin D response element-containing reporter gene plasmids, without altering levels of VDR or endogenous BAG1L protein, suggesting that it operates as a trans-dominant inhibitor of BAG1L. Gene transfer-mediated elevations in BAG1L protein levels in a prostate cancer cell line (PC3), which is moderately responsive to VDR ligands, increased the ability of natural (1 alpha ,25(OH)(2) vitamin D-3) and synthetic (1 alpha ,25-dihydroxy19-nor-22(E)-vitamin D-3) VDR ligands to induce expression of the VDR target gene, p21(Waf1), and suppress DNA synthesis. Thus, BAG1L is a direct regulator of VDR, which enhances its trans-activation function and improves tumor cell responses to growth-suppressive VDR ligands.																	0021-9258					DEC 29	2000	275	52					40749	40756		10.1074/jbc.M004977200						WOS:000166114600014	10967105				
J	Long, XM; Griffith, LC				Long, XM; Griffith, LC			Identification and characterization of a SUMO-1 conjugation system that modifies neuronal calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II in Drosophila melanogaster	JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY												Drosophila Uba2 and Ubc9 SUMO-1 conjugation enzyme homologs (DmUba2 and DmUbc9) were isolated as calcium/calmodulin-dependent kinase II (CaMKII) interacting proteins by yeast two-hybrid screening of an adult head cDNA library. We found that at least one isoform of Drosophila neuronal CaMXII is conjugated to DmSUMO-1 in vivo. The interactions observed in the two-hybrid screen may therefore reflect catalytic events. To understand the role of SUMO conjugation in the brain, we undertook a characterization of the system. The other required components of the system, Drosophila Aos1 and SUMO-1 (DmAos1 and DmSUMO-1), were identified in expressed sequence tag data base searches. Purified recombinant DmUbaB/DmAos1 dimer can activate DmSUMO-1 in vitro and transfer DmSUMO-1 to recombinant DmUbc9. DmSUMO-1 conjugation occurs in all developmental stages of Drosophila and in the adult central nervous system. Overexpression of a putative dominant negative DmUba2(C175S) mutant protein in the Drosophila central nervous system resulted in an increase in overall DmSUMO-1 conjugates and a base-sensitive p120 species, which is likely to be DmUba2(C175S) linked to endogenous DmSUMO-1 through an oxygen ester bond. Overexpression of DmUba2(wt) protein in vivo also led to increased levels of DmSUMO-1 conjugates. High level overexpression of either DmUba2(wt) or DmUba2(C175S) in the Drosophila central nervous system caused pupal and earlier stage lethality. Expression in the developing eye led to a rough eye phenotype with retinal degeneration. These results suggest that normal SUMO conjugation is essential in the differentiated nervous system and reveal a potential novel mechanism that regulates neuronal calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II function.					Griffith, Leslie/0000-0003-3164-9876												0021-9258					DEC 29	2000	275	52					40765	40776		10.1074/jbc.M003949200						WOS:000166114600016	10995744				
J	Wei, LN; Hu, XL; Chandra, D; Seto, E; Farooqui, M				Wei, LN; Hu, XL; Chandra, D; Seto, E; Farooqui, M			Receptor-interacting protein 140 directly recruits histone deacetylases for gene silencing	JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY												Receptor-interacting protein 140 (RIP140) encodes a histone deacetylase (HDAC) inhibitor-sensitive repressive activity. Direct interaction of RIP140 with HDAC1 and HDAC3 occurs in vitro and in vivo as demonstrated in co-immunoprecipitation and glutathione S-transferase pull-down experiments. The HDAC-interacting domain of RIP140 is mapped to its N-terminal domain, between amino acids 78 and 303 based upon glutathione S-transferase pull-down experiments. In chromatin immunoprecipitation assays, it is demonstrated that histone deacetylation occurs at the chromatin region of the Ga14 binding sites as a result of Ga14 DNA binding domain-tethered RIP expression. The immunocomplexes of RIP140 from cells transfected with RIP140 and HDAC are able to deacetylate histone proteins in vitro. This study presents the first evidence for RIP140 as a negative coregulator for nuclear receptor actions by directly recruiting histone deacetylases and categorizes RIP140 as a novel negative coregulator that is able to directly interact with HDACs.																	0021-9258					DEC 29	2000	275	52					40782	40787		10.1074/jbc.M004821200						WOS:000166114600018	11006275				
J	Chen, DG; Huang, SM; Stallcup, MR				Chen, DG; Huang, SM; Stallcup, MR			Synergistic, p160 coactivator-dependent enhancement of estrogen receptor function by CARM1 and p300	JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY												Members of the p160 coactivator family (steroid receptor coactivator-l (SRC-1), glucocorticoid receptor interacting protein 1 (GRIP1), and activator of thyroid and retinoic acid receptors (ACTR)) mediate transcriptional activation by nuclear receptors, After being recruited to the promoter by nuclear receptors, the p160 coactivator transmits the activating signal via two C-terminal activation domains, AD1 and AD2, AD1 is a binding site for the related coactivators cAMP-response element binding protein binding protein (CBP) and p300, whereas AD2 binds to another coactivator, coactivator-associated arginine methyltransferase 1 (CARM1), a protein-arginine methyltransferase. The current study explored the cooperative functional and mechanistic relationships among GRIP1, CARM1, and p300 in transient transfection assays, where they enhanced the ability of the estrogen receptor (ER) to activate transcription of a reporter gene. The coactivator functions of p300 and CARM1 depended on the co-expression of GRIP1. Simultaneous co-expression of all three coactivators caused a synergistic enhancement of ER function. Deletion of the AD1 domain of GRIP1 abolished the ability of p300 to potentiate ER activity but had no effect on CARM1-mediated stimulation. In contrast, when the AD2 domain of GRIP1 was deleted, p300 still stimulated ER function through the mutant GRIP1, but CARM1 failed to do so. Thus, both binding of p300 to AD1 and binding of CARM1 to AD2 are required for their respective coactivator functions and for their synergy. Furthermore, CARM1 and p300 function independently through different activating domains of GRIP1, and their synergy suggests that they enhance transcription by different, complementary. mechanisms.				zhang, shijun/K-3688-2013													0021-9258					DEC 29	2000	275	52					40810	40816		10.1074/jbc.M005459200						WOS:000166114600022	11010967				
